SAMUEL AKINWUSI AWS Architect

samueltos@yahoo.com

4044018879

github.com/samueltos

SUMMARY

I am an experienced software and cloud devops engineer specialized in creating, designing and developing a modern web application and automating cloud infrastructure. Strong passion for architecting highly scalable and redundant infastructure, application in both on-premise and cloud environment.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Solutions Architect-Associate

SKILLS

Experience in Automation, Disaster Recovery, Highly Availability and Scabality, Backup,
 Data Analysis, Data Validation, Web Application.

Programming Language Other Language

Python, Java, PHP, JavaScript. HTML, CSS.

Libraries & Frameworks Design & Prototyping

Angular, Spring boot, Bootstrap. Adobe XD, Figma, Photoshop

Tools & Platforms RDBMS

AWS, WordPress, Microsoft Office, SQL

Visual Studio, IntelliJ, PyCharm

EDUCATION

KENNESAW STATE UNIVERSITY, Kennesaw, GA Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

May 2019

BANGALORE UNIVERSITY, Bangalore, India

Bachelor of Science in Computer Applications

May 2015

WORK EXPERIENCE

Swordcon Solutions, Atlanta GA – Solution Architect Dec. 2018 – Present

- Responsible for migration and implementation of multiple applications from on premise to cloud using CloudFormation, Elastic Beanstalk.
- Designed and provisioned of serverless architecture using Lamba and CloudWatch.
- Deploying and provisioning highly available and scalable application on AWS according to the requirement and architectural frameworks.
- Experience with maintenance and configuration of user accounts for dev, QA and Prod and assigning appropriate roles to each team.
- Provisioning and architecting a virtual private cloud (VPC), create subnets, internet gateway (IGW), route table, security groups, NAT gateway.
- Designing and implementing correct database and storage for handle storing of data and files.
- Creating amazon simple workflow service (SWF) to automate the process of application, track state and coordinator task.
- Using SQS FIFO to automate the process of getting job done sequentially and send notification for change of status of process.
- Providing specifications according to which the solution is defined, managed, and delivered.
- Experience working with Amazon VPC, Amazon EC2, AWS Lamba, Amazon S3, Elastic Block Storage (EBS), Amazon RDS, Amazon DynamoDB, Amazon CloudFormation, Amazon Elastic Beanstalk, Amazon Cloudwatch, VPC Flow Log, SQS, SNS and SWF

Swordcon Solutions, Atlanta GA – Software Engineer July 2018 – Present

- Contribute software engineering expertise in the development of products through the software lifecycle, from requirements definition through successful deployment.
- Introducing methodologies and best practices that enhanced product definition, release processes and customization of applications to user needs.
- Hands on experience with writing SQL queries in MySQL databases.
- Adding features and functionality to existing application using MVC architectural pattern.
- Designing and implementing RESTful services using Spring Boot framework.
- Developing SPA using Angular frameworks based on Typescript.

- Developing User Interface with HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Provisioned EC2 instance as Web Server for applications, routing DNS through route53, securing web application by generating SSL certificate and configuring it to be used by the EC2.
- Backing up instance by taking AMI so that new instance can be provisioned in case of down time or distaster recovery.

MallBeyond LTD, Nigeria – Software Engineer

Sept. 2015 - Aug. 2016

- Actively involved in updating the web application and developing functional requirement for different projects.
- Performed project documentation as assigned by the team lead.
- Writing SQL queries to perform CRUD operation on MySQL database of the application.
 Accessing the interface using MySQL Workbench.
- User Authentication and Authorization are done on the application to enable the user to securely log in and access their profile. Individual profiles are stored as well.